<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community on Swapnil Ogale Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/tags/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community on Swapnil Ogale Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://swapnilogale.github.io/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technical Writing Process, 2nd Edition</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/techwritingbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/techwritingbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working alongside a team of stellar technical communication specialists, I was the lead writer on the Design chapters for the 2nd edition of the Technical Writing Process book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My chapters focussed on the use of stylesheets in document design, and importance of using visuals like screenshots and diagrams in technical documentation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Buy the Technical Writing Process (2nd Edition) today and master the craft of technical writing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Paperback: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Technical-Writing-Process-Timeless-Techniques/dp/0994169329/&#34;&gt;Technical Writing Process (2024, 2nd Ed.) Paperback&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;e-Book: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Technical-Writing-Process-Timeless-Techniques-ebook/dp/B0CV2SKBCG/&#34;&gt;Technical Writing Process (2024, 2nd Ed.) e-Book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embrace Discomfort and Challenge the Status Quo for Advocacy and Visibility</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/insidetechcomm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/insidetechcomm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I chatted with the host of Inside TechComm about:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What does the technical communication landscape look like in Australia?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What is a technical writer advocate?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How I perform my own tech comm retrospective to elevate his role and make it visible?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What is the Amazon narrative, and how can someone use this narrative before starting a project?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What are some strategies to raise the profile of a tech writer at a company and beyond?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech Writer Advocacy and Managing Write the Docs Australia</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/techcommpodcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/publications/techcommpodcast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I chatted with the host of The Not Boring Tech Writer about:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Write the Docs Australia community&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Organising meetups and conference for the Write the Docs Australia community&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Why it is necessary to advocate for good documentation practices&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What my role as a Technical Writer Advocate is all about&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Write the Docs Australia - Community management</title>
      <link>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/contributions/wtd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 12:25:06 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://swapnilogale.github.io/projects/contributions/wtd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.writethedocs.org/&#34;&gt;Write the Docs&lt;/a&gt; is a global community of people who care about documentation. We consider everyone who cares about communication, documentation, and their users to be a member of our community. This can be programmers, tech writers, developer advocates, customer support, marketers, and anyone else who wants people to have great experiences with software.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;contribution&#34;&gt;Contribution&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While we have had other communities in Australia that covered technical documentation sporadically, there was no community for like- minded people to get together and talk about documentation issues. I have been part of other groups that organised technical writing events and conferences in the past, but in 2016, none of these groups existed and there was a serious gap in community events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
